Welcome to the eLearning session
Getting Started with Ensemble:
欢迎来到elearing课程,Ensemble入门：
Technology Adapters.
技术适配器
Business Services and
Business Operations
BS和BO
provide the inbound and
outbound connection points
提供输入输出连接点
for Ensemble Production.
给ensemble产品
While not always required, both
Business Services and Business
虽然不是总需要，BS和BO
Operations use adapters to
achieve this connection.
用适配器来达成这种连接
Business Services
use Inbound Adapters.
BS用输入适配器
And Business Operations
use Outbound Adaptors.
BO用输出适配器
An adapter is a class
that will handle
一个适配器是一个class,它处理
the details of the
technology being
一个技术细节，这个技术
used for the connection, such
as the wire protocol or file
用于连接，比如连接协议或者文件
format, together with
retries and error handling.
格式，还有重传以及错误处理
The Business
Operations and Services
BO和BS
handle the content
at a higher level.
在高层次上处理内容
For a Business Service,
the Inbound Adapter
对于BS,输入适配器
is constantly looking
for work, for example,
不停歇的处于等待状态，比如说
by listening on a
TCP/IP connection port
通过监听TCP/IP连接端口
or monitoring a
directory of files.
或者监视一个文件目录
When it finds work to do, it
calls the method ProcessInput
当它发现有工作要做，它调用BS中的ProcessInput()
of the Business Service, passing
the input as a first parameter.
用输入做第一个参数
And the Business Service
will pass back any response
随后BS传回响应
by reference in the
second parameter.
通过第二个参数，以by reference方式
Let's take a look in
Studio at an adapter class.
让我们在Studio里看看一个适配器class
As you can see, there
are adapters to handle
如你看到的，这里有多个适配器处理
a wide range of technologies--
EDI, HL7, HTTP, SOAP SQL,
一系列的技术- EDI, HL7, HTTP, SOAP, SQL
and so forth.
等等
As an example, let's look
at the File InboundAdapter
例如，让我们看看文件输入适配器(File InboundAdapter)
that is used for picking
up operating system files
它用于抓取操作系统中的文件
and processing them.
并处理他们
Just like the Business
Service or Operation,
就像BS或者BO
an adapter class has settings.
一个适配器class有多个设置
In the case of the
File InboundAdapter,
在File InboundAdapter里
these include the File
Path, Working Directory,
它们包括文件路径, 工作目录
and Archive Directory.
和归档目录
These are properties
of the adapter class.
它们都是适配器class中的property
Other adapters have settings
appropriate to the technology
其他适配器有适合其处理技术的各种设置
they handle.
When you configure a Business
Service in a Production,
当你在产品里配置一个BS
the adapter settings
will appear along
适配器设置会显示出来
with the other settings
of the Business Service.
和这个BS的其他配置一起
If the Business Service
uses an adapter,
如果这个BS用一个适配器
one or more jobs will be started
when the Production is started
当产品启动的时候，一或多个jobs会开始工作
to run the Business Service.
来运行这个BS
The number of jobs is controlled
by the Pool Size setting
jobs的个数由Pool Size设置决定
for the Business Service.
（这个BS的）
When the file adapter is
running in a Business Service,
当文件适配器在一个BS里运行的时候
it will check the FilePath for
files that match the FileSpec.
它会检查文件路径来寻找符合文件类型的文件
If there are any, it will
process them one by one.
如果找到，它就一个个的处理他们
It moves a file to
the work directory,
它把一个文件挪到工作目录
if that has been specified,
reads the file into a stream,
如果(工作目录）被指定，把文件读到一个流里
and passes the stream
to the ProcessInput
然后把流送给BS里面的
method of the Business Service.
ProcessInput()
Upon successful completion
of the Business Service,
一旦这个BS工作成功完成
the file is moved to
the ArchiveDirectory,
这个文件会挪到归档目录
if that has been specified.
如果(归档目录)被指定的话。
If there are no
files to process,
如果没有文件要处理
the adapter will go to
sleep and check again
适配器会进入休眠然后再次工作
after the number of seconds
specified in the Call Interval
在多少秒之后，其在Call Interval设置中
setting.
定义
To include this adapter
in a Business Service,
为了把适配器放到一个BS里
I can use the New
Business Service Wizard
我可以用Studio里面的新BS向导
in Studio, which will
create a class like this.
它创建像这样的一个class
By clicking on New and
selecting Business Service
点击New,选择Business Service
in my Production tab, I
can specify the Package,
在my Production页面，我可以指定一个Package
the Business Service.
BS,
When I click Next, I
have the opportunity
当我点Next,我们就有机会
to select the
appropriate adapter.
选择一个合适的适配器
When I click Finish,
you can see that I
当我们点Finish， 你可以看到我
have the basis of a new
Business Service class.
有了一个新BS类的基本内容
The adapter parameter
has been specified
适配器parameter被指定了
as the file inbound adapter
that I've just selected.
正是我刚刚选择的文件输入适配器
Now, I need to implement the
OnProcessInput method in order
现在，我们需要实现OnProcessInput()
to process, line by line,
the information that
来一行行的处理
was read into the input stream.
被读到输入流的数据
Other Inbound Adapters, such as
the FTP adapter, email adapter,
其他输入适配器，比如FTP适配器，email适配器
or SQL adapter behave
in much the same way,
或者SQL适配器，以差不多相同的方式工作
although the settings
available are different.
虽然要做的设置项目不同
The TCP and HTTP adapters
are slightly different
TCP和HTTP适配器有一点不同
and open a socket and listen for
input continually, rather than
它们是打开一个socket，持续的监听输入
polling at intervals.
而不是以一个时间间隔做轮询，
But the essential
use is the same.
但基本的使用是相同的。
Now we will look at
Outbound Adapters, which are
现在我们看看输出适配器，他们是被
called by Business Operations.
BO调用的
In a Business Operation,
the property ADAPTER
在BO里，property ADAPTER
holds an object reference
to the adapter object
保存一个到适配器对象的对象reference
so you can call methods or
set properties of the adapter.
由此你可以调用methods，或者设置这个适配器的property
Normally, the Outbound Adapter
exposes a few simple methods
一般说，输出适配器暴露一些简单的methods
to make it easy to
call the adapter.
使调用这个适配器容易
Let's look at an example
of a Business Operation
让我们看一个BO的例子
using the SQL Outbound Adapter.
其中用了SQL输出适配器
So we will open
Business Operations,
让我们打开BO
eLearning, SQLOperation.
When using the Business
Operation Wizard,
当使用BO向导
you define the adapter to
be used for this Business
你定义了这个BO用的适配器
Operation, and that value
becomes the ADAPTER property.
其中值是适配器的property
That makes coding the
Business Operation much easier
这使得BO的代码编写更容易
since the adapter methods and
properties are now exposed
因为适配器methods和properties现在都暴露
to the Business Operation.
给BO
I can set properties
of the adapter.
我可以设置这个适配器的properties
For example, in
my OnInit method,
比如，在我的 OnInit()
I have set the timeout in
the Statement,Attrs property.
我在Adapter.StatementAttrs里设置了超时时长
The main properties
of each adapter
每个适配器主要的properties
are exposed through
the configuration
被暴露出来，通过产品的
page of the Production.
配置页
So the values can be set either
in the configuration item,
所以值可以设置在配置项里，
or they can be set in the
Business Operation code.
或者设置在BO程序代码里
The MessageMap defines
the post-message method
MessageMap定义了收到消息后的method
for StringRequest messages
that are sent to this Business
这里消息是指发给BO的StringRequest消息
Operation.
In this case, SQL
inserts the text content
在这个例子里， SQL插入了StringRequest的文本内容
of my StringRequest message
into one column and the time
到一栏里，而时间
and date into another column.
和日期到另一栏
The SQL Outbound
Adapter also has methods
SQL输出适配器还拥有methods
to execute queries and updates.
来执行查询和更新
When working with
any adapter, you
当使用任何适配器的时候
will find the online class
reference in our documentation
你可以找到在线文档
to be very useful for seeing
what methods and properties are
对发现(适配器)都提供什么property和method
available.
非常有用
If we take a look
at the configuration
如果我们看一下产品配置页面
page of a Production, we can
add the SQL Business Operation
我们可以加入SQL BO
to the Production, simply
selecting it from the list,
到产品，简单的从列表里面选择它
giving it a name, making
sure it's enabled so that it
起个名字，确定Enable选中了这样它
can be used, and clicking OK.
才可以被使用，点击ok
If we take a look
at this operation,
如果你看一下这个BO
you can see in the
Settings the adapter class
你可以在Setting里看到正在使用的Adapter class
that's being utilized, the class
for the Business Operation,
还有BO的class
as well as information that
would be required for a SQL
还包括SQL连接需要的信息
connection, for example, the DSN
credentials, potentially JDBC
比如DSN, credentials, 或者JDBC
driver information, as well.
驱动信息
Thank you for listening
to this session Getting
您刚刚看的是‘Ensemble入门-
Started with Ensemble:
Technology Adapters.
技术适配器